JUNGLE EMPEROR
On the African continent, there is
a valley that runs north to south.
It is called the Great Rift Valley.
Although called a valley, its vastness
is as though the earth was ripped open.
To the west of the valley
are the jungle of Congo,
to the east are the savannas
of Uganda and Kenya,
to the north is the Nile River
that runs from Lake Victoria
and also the Sahara desert.
For a long time,
the rugged nature of these lands
prevented Africa
from having civilized culture
and so it had been called
the Dark Continent.
But it's different now.
Day has dawned in Africa.
In the 20th century,
Africa is embarking on a journey towards
building a bright new civilized culture.
However, if you leave
the bright world of humankind
and take one step into the jungle…
it is still the Dark Continent.
There are the law of the jungle,
where the strong survive
and the weak are annihilated,
and death.
This story begins in an animal kingdom
located in the jungle near the equator.
Panja's queen is here?
Yes. Her Majesty Queen Eliza is on board.
Hooray!
No, stupid.
She was captured by humans.
And, also
the poor queen is about to have a baby.
Why don't we all support her?
Agreed!
Thank you all for agreeing right away.
Let's start right now!
The baby has arrived.
He's an all-white, cute little boy.
A little over a month has now passed.
All the animals were sold off
at various ports,
but, Panja's queen Eliza
was still on board the ship.
Hey, who's this?
Ah, that's this girl's father.
Where's my father?
Well, that's…
Come over here, son.
What is it, Mommy?
A lion's cub is no longer a baby
when they've grown to about your size.
So today, I'm going to tell you
the story of your father, Panja.
Panja was a very smart and brave lion.
Your father Panja
always protected all the animals
from the humans
who came to vandalize the jungle.
The white lion hasn't shown up at all.
He must be intimidated by the sight of us.
Keep looking. He's somewhere around here.
There he is!
Let me handle this!
Hey, give me the rifle!
Oh no!
Our animals are escaping!
Drat!
Father was so strong, wasn't he?
Not only was he strong,
he was also very kind.
And that is why
so many weak little animals
liked to gather around Panja.
What? We're going to have a baby?
Yes, dear.
Congratulations,
Queen Eliza and King Panja!
Congratulations!
Thank you.
I'll go check it out.
Did someone get eaten again?
Am I too late?
Your Majesty. A lone monkey was attacked.
It was the panther as usual.
I've punished him before.
This is unacceptable.
It's no use.
They're all the same, Your Majesty.
They all go insane when they get hungry.
They're here for the remains.
Your Majesty!
Mandy, where's Panja?
He's gone.
Did he go to the humans' village again
to get livestock?
Yes, probably…
He's putting himself in so much danger.
The amount of meat he brings back,
won't fill the stomachs
of all the animals in the jungle anyway.
Your Majesty.
King Panja is definitely
wise enough to know that.
He must go even though
he understands the limitations.
I had more faith in you!
I didn't intend to invite someone
so useless all the way from London.
The Janga people are furious.
Lion hunting might be a sport to you,
but it's a matter
of life or death to them.
Pigs and cattle are their livelihoods…
-But sir--
-But the white lion steals
all of their livestock.
When the villagers
went hunting for the white lion,
five or six of them were attacked.
As the wildlife management officer,
I was consulted.
So I called you, a certified hunter.
I had more faith in you!
I didn't intend to invite someone
so useless all the way from London.
There he goes again.
It's his fifth time already.
That's what he told you?
Lions that steal livestock are usually
crippled or over the hill.
But this one's different.
According to the management officer,
he seems to be protecting weak animals.
But livestock are weak animals, too.
To the animals of the jungle, animals
on the human's side must be traitors.
I just heard a cow.
It's too late to shoot him.
Watch this.
Mr. Ham-and-egg! That lion is here!
What are you doing?
I'm recording.
-What?
-Officer.
You told me that the lion
has a female partner, didn't you?
Yes, I said that. So?
Excellent.
Just watch,
I'll definitely catch him tomorrow
with this secret weapon.
The very next day,
the evil humans came again.
Panja?
He's supposed to be in the forest
battling the humans. That's strange.
It's a trap!
Panja! Don't come here! Panja!
If you come, the humans will kill you!
Stay back, Panja!
Eliza.
Panja.
I've come up with a good name.
The name for
our soon-to-be-born son will be Leo.
Please name him Leo.
That is the story of your father.
You must become a son
worthy of your father's name.
Do you understand, Leo?
Yes.
Leo.
That's a good name.
You must sneak off
of this ship immediately
and return to Africa, to the jungle.
Yes, Mommy.
Aren't you coming?
I'm trapped in this cage.
You must go alone.
No!
I don't want to leave without you, Mommy!
I don't want to!
There is no other way.
Leo.
Do you think you're behaving
like Panja's son should?
That's cruel. Leo is still so little.
Listen carefully.
This ship will be sinking soon.
S-Sinking?
Only animals can sense it.
S-So she's letting her son go before--
They're hunting for mice!
How terrible!
I know, I'll go and help them!
Wait. If you are brave enough
to help them,
why can't you go to Africa?
The jungle is even worse than here.
Goodbye, my son.
Goodbye, Mommy.
Mommy!
Don't get in the way.
Can't you swim any faster?
But I can't swim.
For goodness’ sake! Just wait here.
Mr. Tuna will teach you, little boy.
Move your tail fin.
I don't have one.
Isn't this your tail fin?
Now watch closely.
Keep your body flat like so.
Yes, that's it.
Now breathe out.
Firstly, open your wings.
Then you ride along on the air.
Kick the water like this, see?
Good grief. I've never seen a fish
who's as bad at swimming as you are.
Give up on swimming and travel on this.
Humans use these to travel sometimes too.
Wow! This is fast!
He's so hopeless,
he's happy just to be pushed along by us.
A saw shark!
-You did it!
-Well done!
That was brilliant, little boy.
And you were swimming with no problem.
Don't forget how you just swam.
Go on your way with caution.
Don't feel lonely, Leo
Mommy is with you, Leo
Mommy is here
I'm in the stars now
Mommy!
I'm watching you from the sky
I'm shining my light on you
Go on, Leo
Never stop, Leo
Mommy's dearest child
Leo
Oh, butterflies!
I must be near land.
It's Africa!
Africa!
Leo returned to Africa
and headed towards his homeland
which he had never seen.
He lost his way many times,
and he felt like giving up many times.
But Leo kept walking.
What Leo saw
on his way
was a horrifying world
where animals were killing each other.
A few months have now passed
and Leo has grown a little bit larger.
Hey, wait!
Hey, you hyenas over there!
Hmm?
Huh?
Why are you ganging up on Mr. Antelope?
Poor Mr. Antelope is shivering.
Let him go!
Are you trying to stop us? That's funny.
You'd better not move, little boy.
I'll deal with you later
after we finish off that one.
But I've never seen his face
around here before. Have you, Bo?
I haven't either, Dick.
I guess we should
introduce ourselves, then.
-I guess.
-Right, Bo?
Let's show him who we are.
We are
The very hungry
Hyena gang
I'm Dick
I'm Bo
Together we are
-Dimwit Duo
-Wrong!
Together we are Dick and Bo
To the powerful
We bow down
To the powerless
We are big and strong
Are you ready?
Here we go!
One
Two
One, two, three
Go!
Mr. Antelope!
May I ask you something?
Y-Yes. What could it be?
Have you seen anyone named
Panja around here?
Panja? Panja was certainly here.
Everyone. Panja Jr. has returned!
Come to the clearing in the forest.
Everybody is there.
Panja Jr.?
Yes.
Leo is back!
Look how he's completely white
just like his father!
Don't brag just because you found him.
I've always thought this day would come.
To celebrate today's happy occasion,
we decided to have a festival.
Look at that.
Leo.
I'm Samson the buffalo.
I have just brought offerings
for the festival.
Would you accept them?
Yes. I'd be happy to.
What's the matter?
Those mules are the offerings
for the festival.
W-What?
I just kidnapped them from
the Janga village. They're livestock.
Let's have a good time
while eating these mules.
You should go first, Leo.
Are you saying I should kill and eat them?
Exactly.
When Panja was here,
we had festivals like these often.
What are you waiting for, Leo?
Just have a bite.
Aren't you going to eat our offering, Leo?
Of course not.
I'm going to return them to the village.
What? That's ridiculous.
Did you hear him, everybody?
Is this really the son
of the mighty Panja?
Leo. I'm disappointed in you.
I'll show you a true jungle animal.
Just watch!
Look out!
You barbaric bull!
You traitor!
Grandpa Mandy, we must do something now.
Calm down, Tommy.
I think the little son does have a spine
unlike you all.
But Leo might get squashed.
Well, that would be that then.
You must all calm down.
Coco is such a show-off.
Well, Samson, I can see why you're upset--
Be quiet!
How dare he!
Just watch, I'll cook him into a steak!
No, you're the one who'll be squashed.
What…
He's right. So stop getting in the way
and stay right there.
Hmm. I see you do have courage
as you should. Fine.
If you don't want to eat them, then don't.
But in that case,
nobody will call you the son of Panja.
Is that really okay with you, Leo?
Come with me.
I feel sorry for him.
W-Where are you going?
To the village of Janga.
To do what?
Shh.
I'll go take a peek.
Will he be okay? Birds are night-blind.
Ouch!
Ow…
Pull yourself together.
Did you see the lion's skin?
I did. It is hung on the wall.
All right. Then let's get started.
Please wait!
Father?
Are you my father?
Your father is right here.
You are my father as I thought!
Father!
Now now, you are not free to come near me.
Today, you have
misplaced my name.
Misplaced?
I mean, displaced…
Or was it replaced?
Did I get it wrong?
You idiot. I wanted you to say,
"You have disgraced my name."
What I mean is,
you have disgraced my name.
That did happen.
I'm sorry, Father.
-You fool!
-Huh?
It is only natural for younger generations
to try new ways to do things.
I am actually happy that you erased…
I mean disgraced my name.
"Son, you are Panja's child.
Have courage and honor.
Behave with dignity."
Listen, son.
That's good.
You are Panja's child.
But
everybody in the jungle says
I'm not your son.
You fool!
What?
Don't be such a coward.
You shouldn't let them say such things.
Do you mean it, Father?
Sooner or later, they will understand
that you did the right thing.
Be confident.
Good evening.
-I'm sorry!
-You tricked me!
How dare you
use my father's skin to play a prank!
What do you think you're doing?
Why did you do something like this?
Leo, do we look like we want to harm you?
Grampa Mandy, Tommy, Coco,
do you really think I did the right thing?
I understand.
Thank you, everyone.
Thanks to you, I feel better now.
Someday, Samson and the others
will figure out how I feel.
Hooray for Leo!
Hooray!
Please watch over me.
Wildfire!
A wildfire has broken out in the jungle.
Everybody run!
Wildfires are common in the dry season
when there's a long period of no rain.
Still, it is always unfortunate
for those animals who are affected.
So much of the savanna is burned.
But it's good the fire didn't spread.
I was surprised and thought
humans might have caused it.
Humans have ways
to make fields for agriculture
by burning a part of the jungle
to scorch the trees.
Hey! Maybe we should make
our own vegetable fields!
Our own vegetable fields?
Then we wouldn't have to
kill and eat each other!
Is this child insane?
Or is he--
What do you all think?
He must be insane!
That's for sure!
We can never make our own fields.
That's true!
Poor Queen Eliza…
That's right!
Be quiet!
It's okay if you don't want to do it.
I'll do it by myself.
Hup. There it goes.
Mmph…
What are you doing, everybody?
Laiya.
Why are you making Leo do all the work?
And you call yourselves males? Huh?
L-Laiya.
Hey, Leo. I'll help you.
If you'll help me,
I won't need anybody else.
Drat. Should we just let her
insult us like that?
No way. I'll show her that Zoro is a male.
Tachi is a male too.
Heave-ho…
What should we do?
I know. I'm a male too. Let's go.
What?
Grandpa Mandy.
I've made a decision.
We should grow our own vegetables
and maybe open a restaurant.
Wow! That'll be great!
We're carving rocks
Chopping down huge trees
We work up a sweat
Until we're starving
Our four legs standing firm
Are starting to shake
But none of us are lazy
Let's do our best
Making fields out of the jungle
Let's make a nice field for the village
The morning sun rises
The evening sun sets
We work all night
We have stopped taking naps
Our eyes are starting to get blurry
But we can all take it
Let's do our best
Making fields out of the jungle
Our restaurant will be completed soon
Hey, don't push me.
Hurry.
Get in line to enter.
Everybody, please come!
This is an invitation to
the opening of Mandy's Restaurant.
The restaurant has opened!
You should come too, birds.
So many delicious items on the menu.
Huh?
You shouldn't eat that.
That's an invitation ticket.
I don't know what you mean,
but I'm so very hungry.
I mean if you take this ticket
to Mandy's Restaurant,
you can eat everything for free.
That sounds nice.
I should head on over right away.
Hey, everybody. Hurry.
Whoa.
What a large group of diners.
Excuse me, where's my food?
Hey, hurry up.
I ordered green grass.
I ordered a fruit of banabana.
Okay, one green grass,
one fruit of banabana, please.
I'll be right there! Whew, so busy.
Can I have some coconut juice?
Coming right up!
Hey, Tommy. Get me a coconut.
I can't climb trees.
See if there are any on the ground.
It looks difficult for Mr. Giraffe to eat
because of his long neck.
How about you, Leo?
Are you done eating?
-Hmm?
-Yeah.
I was done eating a long time ago.
Leo.
Samson.
I'm impressed by you.
W-What are you saying, Samson?
You are truly fit to be Panja's son.
Everybody seems to be having a good time.
I'd like to be a part of it too.
That would be fine, wouldn't it, Leo?
Yay!
That's perfectly fine, Mr. Samson.
Leo, do you want to race?
I would love to.
Hang on a minute, Leo!
Grandpa Mandy.
We want to see the sunset
in the desert to the west.
Since today's work is done,
why not come with us?
Leo.
Goodbye.
-Whee!
-Hooray!
Wow.
It's so pretty.
What's that?
T-The sun broke in two.
No, that's just a whirlwind.
Whoa. That was strong.
A sunset and a whirlwind.
It's a worrisome combination.
Why?
Haven't you heard the rumors
about the Gods of Death?
There are three of them.
When the sun sets,
they appear from behind a whirlwind.
That's what they say…
Hmm?
Beware
The three Gods of Death are coming
Sammy the fang cat
Dave the giant elephant
Junior the baboon
Nothing left
After they pass through
Not even a bone
The Gods of Death…?
Stand back, little boy.
Hey, are you the Gods of Death?
Why are you called that?
Why are we the Gods of Death?
Show him, Sammy.
Okay.
Hey! What are you doing?
Leo. Don't mess with them.
Do you get it now, little boy?
He doesn't seem to get it yet, Junior.
Leo!
Leo?
I get it.
Just don't come to the jungle,
Gods of Death!
Do you think you can stop us, Leo?
That's not possible.
Thanks for letting us through.
What in the world is happening?
This looks like a convenient place.
Good timing. Everybody, bring food.
Dave is outside and he's hungry.
Hey you. The gigantic one.
What's going on?
Why don't you introduce yourself?
Just because you're a bit bigger,
doesn't mean you're better than us.
Look at me. Although my body is this size,
I'm loved by everybody here.
W-What are you trying to do?
If you use violence, you'll be sorry!
Uh-oh…
Ouch.
Do you get it now?
Then bring us more food!
-Those guys--
-They're really strong.
Even Leo got clobbered.
What?
Is that true?
That was nothing. All you have to do is
keep feeding us and we won't bother you.
Don't just stand there. They need food.
Hurry up and do what they say.
This amount won't do at all.
We need a lot more than this.
Yes, sir!
Hey, that was not enough.
Get them everything you have.
Everything? We have to ask Grampa Mandy.
It doesn't matter what Grampa Mandy says.
We can't make them angry.
It's too dangerous.
You need to hurry!
Okay. That should do it.
Right, Dave?
I think we've gone far enough
that they won't find us.
Get down now, Leo.
No!
I want to fight them!
Leo! You must not!
You're no match for them.
Calm down and listen.
For a while, until your wounds heal,
stay right here!
Grandpa Mandy, are you going to
let Leo fight after he heals?
Of course not.
Get out of the way!
Big Dave is coming through!
I don't know who this Dave is,
but he doesn't scare me.
I'll drink water like always.
-Whoa!
-That's amazing.
He's truly amazing.
Darn it! It's not fair!
I can't take it anymore!
Wow. They're amazing.
They're truly amazing.
This can't be allowed!
We can't let them keep doing
whatever they want any longer!
-Watch me!
-Stop!
Are you going to see Leo again?
Yes. I'm going to train Leo
so he can defeat the Gods of Death.
I'll show them what I got--
It's no use!
You've lived in the Jungle
for quite a while, Coco the parrot.
No matter how much Leo tries,
they are physically undefeatable
Can't you see that?
You scatterbrain.
They've turned many jungles
into graveyards all around Africa.
The Gods of Death are
exactly what they are.
Before they eat up
all our grass and all of us too,
as they did to other areas,
we should get together and flee.
Do you understand, Coco?
As soon as Leo's wounds are healed,
that's what we'll do.
No. That wasn't good enough.
They are the Gods of Death
who roam all around Africa.
They know the habits of lions very well.
See? Once to the left
and once to the right.
Duck to avoid the tusks.
Use your tail to hit their eyes.
Finally, bite his sore spot, the nose…
Go on, do it!
Aim for the target here, Leo.
I'm ready.
You failed.
No. Not good.
You could do better.
If your heart's not in it,
then maybe you should give up.
Do you want to abandon the jungle
and flee like Grandpa Mandy says?
Please, Leo, be strong.
Become stronger. I beg of you.
I can't do it, Coco.
-It's too hard for me.
-Don't cry, Leo.
I'm the one forcing you
to do something impossible.
The grass we're growing is running short.
Coco, where's Leo?
The jungle is being vandalized.
Well, he has things to do and…
If you would excuse me…
Coco.
Wait, Coco.
There's something going on.
He seemed to be hiding Leo. Didn't he?
I'm sorry, Father.
I'm at the point of giving up.
Even though
the most important battle is near…
Father.
Father
Please answer me, Father
Please give me strength, Father
Wonderful strength
Like your mane
My father who was strong
I'm trying to be coddled.
How embarrassing.
I can't help it because his body is warm
Father
When I'm wrapped in my father's fur,
I feel something flowing into my body.
Father.
This…
This is strength, right?
Argh.
Good. That's it.
You're almost there, Leo.
Leo.
Hang in there, Leo.
I won't bother you.
We can't put it off any longer.
Pay attention.
I'll repeat it one more time.
They must never find us.
In order to do that,
we'll flee in small numbers.
By all means, do not panic.
Do not make loud noises.
Do you understand?
Keep quiet.
Hey, Sammy!
What's the matter, Junior?
They did it.
The essential animals are all gone.
This jungle is completely empty.
You messed up, Junior.
But I guess it's all right.
Wait a minute, Dave!
Don't be angry at us, Dave.
Look, there's something left
that we can eat.
You're right.
Come over here, you three.
Good job bringing us food.
Good boys.
-You won't feel a thing while I eat you.
-Stay away from us!
H-Help!
What was that? I heard children screaming.
It's difficult for me too.
Being chosen by the Gods of Death
was our bad luck.
Let's move to another jungle
and start over from the beginning.
Never! I don't want to!
I don't want to flee from here!
Poor Leo. It must have been
a shocking experience for him.
Even so,
we can't let him act out like this.
Leo!
Come out!
How dare you throw
my father's fur, Grandpa!
So what if I did?
You stubborn child!
You're mean, Grandpa.
Leo!
The trio has been eaten!
And Coco was…
Coco was captured!
You've got to rescue him quickly!
No. You cannot go.
Think carefully, Leo.
If you get caught up in this,
we might lose all the animals.
We should move everybody to safety first.
Leo, please leave the jungle with us.
Grandpa, you're being kind of cruel.
What will happen to Coco?
I will go rescue Coco.
If you don't hurry, it might be too late…
Grandpa, I'll go.
Leo! Are you going to disobey
what this elder says?
Please, Grandpa.
I want another chance
to try out my strength.
Please.
Those three were good animals.
Coco is too.
There's no way you can stop me, Grandpa.
Well well.
You two are definitely father and son.
You're behaving in the same exact way
King Panja did on that day.
What?
That was the last day
I saw your father alive.
That morning, that day…
I tried to stop your father from going.
It's too dangerous! If you go now,
you will surely be trapped by humans.
I know. But still, I have to go.
Your Majesty!
Are you going to disobey
what this elder says?
This is my duty.
I've been fighting those
who bring calamity to this jungle.
This morning,
Eliza was captured by those humans.
She is waiting for me…
Even if this is to be my last day.
I hope you live happily with your mother.
With those last words,
King Panja ran
straight towards your mother
who was trapped in a cage.
Go, Leo.
I won't stop you anymore.
Do your best to fight!
Leo!
His mane shining
Thunder rolling
He pierces through the storm
Leo the white lion
Taking on a challenge
His dream for happiness
He brings the morning
To the jungle
On the infinite road
Leo advances
His mane flows
The vast savanna
Chest held out in the wilderness
Leo the white lion
His good friends
are ringing a bell
A song he sings
Bounces through the jungle
Steady on the road
Leo advances
So you're saying
you don't know where everybody went?
Then we don't need you anymore.
Just wait a second.
What?
Let's each eat half of him.
Drat.
Stop right there!
Who's that?
It's Leo!
I knew he would come to save me.
You're here.
The all-white little boy.
You're still alive?
It looks like you've improved, boy.
Leo. We're not done yet.
H-He went around to the back.
Where did he go?
Show yourself, white one!
I'm over here!
Dave, he's on top of that cliff.
Yay!
He did it!
Hooray!
Leo!
Grandpa Mandy, why didn't you flee?
Don't be silly.
I can't just leave you and run.
That's heartless.
Leo.
How is your wound?
Don't do that. It tickles.
Can you walk?
Uh-huh.
Farewell, strong little boy.
Leo, I hope you keep protecting us
like your father King Panja used to.
Please protect us, Leo.
-We want you to.
-Please do.
I will!
I'll try my best.
Looking back, I think we were too weak.
Fleeing is not the only smart choice.
If only you put your mind to it,
a little boy like Leo can succeed.
From now on,
let's combine our efforts
and confront our enemies together.
Well,
I guess we should go home.
There's work to do in the fields tomorrow.
I'm getting sleepy.
His body is small, but in essence,
he's the mighty emperor of the jungle.
Isn't he, Coco?
I wish King Panja and Queen Eliza
were here to…
see him.
THE END
Subtitle translation by: Ikuko Sachs